# Nofil Qasim

Lahore, 54782 Punjab, Pakistan +92 302 8445808

Github: papadoxie LinkedIn: nofil-gasim Email: nofilqasim@gmail.com

#### Research Interests

My research interests lie in the intersection of computer security and low-level systems. I am interested in the security vulnerabilities posed by systems and language design flaws, and how they can be exploited. Examples of such vulnerabilities include Spectre, Meltdown and PACMAN, and, flaws in the WebAssembly specification which I am currently investigating.

#### Education

# PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

• Expected graduation: July 2023

• GPA: 3.54/4.0

## Lahore Grammar School Johar Town

A Level

**Aitchison College** O Level

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan 2007 - 2017

September, 2019 - Present

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

2017 - 2019

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

## Research Experience

# A Novel Approach to Applying x86-64 Exploitation Techniques on WebAssembly Binaries

November, 2022 - Present

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Supervisor: Dr. Muhammad Arif Butt
- Formulated the idea and initiated the research project
- Discovered differences between WebAssembly Modules built from the same source
- Worked on problems related to fuzzing WebAssembly binaries
- Working on identifying ways to reuse x86-64 exploitation techniques on WebAssembly binaries

# Salient Features of the MIPS32/64 Architecture and A Handy Guideline to its Assembly **Programming**

September, 2022 – Present

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Supervisor: Dr. Muhammad Arif Butt
- Worked on the final draft of the paper

## Professional Experience

#### Malware Researcher

Ebryx (Pvt.) Ltd.

• Worked on Linux Usermode and Kernel Exploitation

- Windows Kernel Exploit PoC Testing
- Initial Access and Malware Deployment Techniques
- AV and EDR Evasion Techniques
- Red Team Capability Development (C2, Phishing, etc.)
- Security Mechanism Bypassing Techniques (Applocker, etc.)

November, 2021 - Present Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

## Teaching Assistant (Operating Systems)

February, 2022 - October, 2022

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

- Designed material and coursework for the newly introduced lab component of the subject
- Designed exam papers for the lab
- Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities

## **Information Security Intern**

July, 2021 - September, 2021

**Systems Limited** 

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

- Level 1 Security Operations Center (SOC) Analysis
- Web Application Penetration Testing

## Teaching Assistant (Computer Organization and Assembly)

February, 2021 - June, 2021

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Redesigned lab material for the semester

Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities

# **Interesting Projects**

#### WASM Research Documentation

WebAssembly, C, Rust

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

https://github.com/papadoxie/WASM-Research-Docs

- · A collection of research papers and documentation on WebAssembly
- Includes a detailed account of my research on WebAssembly

## OS Development

C, x86-64 Assembly

https://github.com/papadoxie/Operating-System

A hobby Operating System with the design philosophy of supporting all major platforms

## Extracurriculars & Volunteering

## Cyber Security Lead

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Google Developer Student Clubs

2020 - 2021 & 2022 - Present

- Conducted workshops on Cyber Security and low-level systems
- E.g. Intro to Security, Deep Dive into C Programming, Memory Corruption and Buffer Overflows.

**University Lead BSides International BSides Pakistan** 2020 - Present

Responsible for building a community of security enthusiasts at my University

#### Mentor and Helper

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Helping Hands Society

2020 - Present

- Helped students with their coursework and assignments
- Mentored students in their projects
- Helped students with core concepts of their subjects

## Co-Founder

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Cyber@PU - Unofficial PUCIT Cyber Security Community

2021

- Faculty Contact: Dr. Muhammad Arif Butt
- Organized a CTF team for the first time in PUCIT
- Work with GDSC PUCIT to organize workshops and seminars

#### Skills

Programming Languages: C, Python, Java, C#, Rust, x86-64 Assembly, LaTeX

Security: Binary Exploitation, Reverse Engineering, Malware Development

Tools: Ghidra, Radare Cutter, GDB, GNU/Make

OS: GNU/Linux, Windows + WSL

# Courses & MOOCs

Malware Analysis: TryHackMe

Incident Response and Forensics: TryHackMe Reverse Engineering 101: Malware Unicorn

Introduction to CyberSecurity Tools & Cyber Attacks: IBM + Coursera